Kyle Schwartz



ABOUT ME

I am a hardworking and dedicated university student who loves computers in their entirety. Computers allow me to be creative, problem solve, and express myself in many facets including graphic and web design as well as coding. I am self-taught in Photoshop, Premiere Pro, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, and Microsoft Office Suite. Formally, I've learnt Java, Adobe Animate, Android Development, and Turing. In my spare time, I decompress by cooking, woodworking, and rowing. I also love to travel around the world and experience different cultures.

EXPERIENCE

Sanofi Pasteur

Toronto

University Internship Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

As a member of the Quality Control, Data Logistics and Support department, I assist my team in modernizing internal tools and improving workflows to maximize efficiency. Additionally, I document internal processes to ensure consistency and compliance in the future.

Camp Green Acres

Markham

Summer Camp Counsellor Jun 2016 - Aug 2019

I worked as a staff member with young children ranging from 5 to 8 years of age in a fun, challenging, and supportive environment. In my second and third summers I was given the additional responsibility of being a bus captain; overseeing 3 staff members. This leadership experience afforded me the opportunity to understand team management and collaboration.

Grip Limited (now dentsu One) **Toronto**

Cooperative Education Placement Feb 2018 - May 2018

I worked in both the technology and video production departments, learning a great deal about corporate structure and how a business functions. I leveraged my knowledge of python to efficiently extract vendor data from excel workbooks, allowing for faster operations.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Student Certificate of Achievement

OCEA | May 2018

Awarded for individual success and participation in the Cooperative Education Program.

Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Google Digital Garage | Cert ID: MKC VS3 H3C | Oct 2018

Ontario Scholar

TDSB | Jun 2018

Awarded for obtaining an average above eighty percent in any six Grade 12 courses.

Interactive Media Certificate

FIT | Cert ID: 5766 | Jun 2018

Software Design & Development

FIT | Cert ID: 5891 | Jun 2018

Excellence in Computer Science

TDSB | Apr 2017

I received the top award for academic excellence in the field of computer science. As a result of this award, I was hand-selected to be placed in an advanced placement (AP) program for the 2017-2018 school year.

PORTFOLIO

Fossil 🖸

A self-hosted static file server for Docker built with Deno

svelte-spins ☑

A zero dependency spinner/loader library using loaders.css as Svelte components

ZoomCube ☑

A minimal Rubik's Cube timer written in Svelte

PDF Press ☑

Serverless PDF generator for Docusaurus and other SSGs

VSCStore ☑

A simple package to add the VSCode marketplace to VSCodium

A Snowpack plugin to convert YAML files to ESM

EDUCATION

High School Diploma

Sep 2014 - Jun 2018

William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York

BSc Computer Science,

Minor in Economics

Sep 2018 - Jan 2023 (Expected)

Lassonde School of Engineering, York University, Toronto

VOLUNTEER WORK

Youth Council President

Beth David Synagogue, North York Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

After successfully running for President, I continued to create, organize, and run engaging programs for the youth in my community. My role as President was to guide and oversee my board and implement the strategic direction provided by our Youth Director.

President of Accounting & Finance Club

William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

I presented seminars on various forms of investment including cryptocurrencies and how to safely invest as markets can be very volatile.

Head Engineer for Engineering Club

William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

As an integral team member, I advised on the programming of our weekly activities to ensure the events were fun and informative for our members.

Computer Programming Team

William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

I led a group of my peers in our school's coding competitions. We placed top 5 in multiple events. In addition, I was selected to be a coach for the visiting grade 7 & 8 students when they participated in our annual Science & Engineering Olympics.